<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>GAME LOG on RD&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GAME LOG on RD&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Borderlands 3: pure chaos, solo fun</title>
      <link>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/borderland3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/borderland3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since picking up &lt;em&gt;Borderlands 3&lt;/em&gt;, I’ve spent most evenings blowing things up as &lt;strong&gt;Moze&lt;/strong&gt;, the Gunner. She’s perfect when you just want to log in, fire up &lt;strong&gt;Iron Bear&lt;/strong&gt;, and let the explosions do the talking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-moze&#34;&gt;Why Moze?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked her for the &lt;strong&gt;mech&lt;/strong&gt; — no deep reason. But turns out she’s super versatile:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explosives-heavy builds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infinite ammo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tanky Iron Bear uptime&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went full &lt;strong&gt;explosives&lt;/strong&gt;. Torgue shotguns, sticky bombs, MIRV grenades, Iron Bear rocket pods. Big booms, fast clears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;playing-solo-just-works&#34;&gt;Playing Solo Just Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, co-op is fun. But solo lets me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore at my own pace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retry bosses without pressure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy the chaos on my terms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I just walk through zones, listen to ambient sounds — then drop Iron Bear and wipe everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-go-to-build-explosive-moze&#34;&gt;My Go-To Build (Explosive Moze)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;weapons&#34;&gt;Weapons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Torgue shotguns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COV rifles&lt;/strong&gt; for sustained fire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anointment: &lt;strong&gt;+100% splash while Iron Bear active&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;grenades&#34;&gt;Grenades&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MIRV + elemental effects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iron-bear&#34;&gt;Iron Bear&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vanquisher Rocket Pods x2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auto Bear&lt;/strong&gt; for extra DPS and distraction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-skills-demolition-woman&#34;&gt;Key Skills (Demolition Woman)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fire in the Skag Den&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pull the Holy Pin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Short Fuse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every shot and grenade is a chance for chain explosions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gris &amp; Neva: beautiful art!!</title>
      <link>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/gris/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/gris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 style=&#34;color:#2a72b9;&#34;&gt;Gris: No Enemies, No Words, Still Works&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gris&lt;/em&gt; is a platformer without combat.&lt;br&gt;
You move, jump, unlock a few abilities, and that’s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the way the environment shifts — from black and white to color, from stillness to motion — carries the whole experience.&lt;br&gt;
No tutorials, no dialogue. Just visual storytelling done right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music is subtle but effective. It feels more like an interactive short film than a “game,” and that’s not a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want something short, quiet, and artistically sharp, &lt;em&gt;Gris&lt;/em&gt; is solid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 style=&#34;color:#3e8e41;&#34;&gt;Neva: Same Style, Different Mood&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neva&lt;/em&gt; is from the same studio, but it leans more into nature, movement, and mood swings.&lt;br&gt;
You explore a forest with a companion creature, solve environmental puzzles, and figure things out as you go — no hand-holding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The animation is smooth, the creature design is great, and the environments shift between beautiful and unsettling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Takes Two — A Game We Played Together</title>
      <link>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/itt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/itt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I played &lt;strong&gt;It Takes Two&lt;/strong&gt; with ZGY.&lt;br&gt;
It’s one of the most memorable co-op games we’ve ever played — full of creativity, fun, and emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the very beginning, when we figured out how to move those little toy figures, to all the crazy puzzle mechanics that forced us to communicate and cooperate, we laughed, struggled, and sometimes just stared at the screen wondering what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game had some &lt;strong&gt;painful&lt;/strong&gt; parts too (yes, that elephant scene — still hurts to think about it). But mostly, it was about learning to be a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, when we reached &lt;strong&gt;the attic&lt;/strong&gt;, and that &lt;strong&gt;letter appeared&lt;/strong&gt;, I realized that’s exactly what I wanted to say to ZGY.&lt;br&gt;
So here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Cody to May:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#83bdd6;&#34;&gt;I miss you and long for you every minute of the day.&lt;br&gt;
The only time I&amp;rsquo;m not missing you is when I&amp;rsquo;m asleep,&lt;br&gt;
but even then, I&amp;rsquo;m dreaming about you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detroit: Become Human — A Game About Choices and Humanity</title>
      <link>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/detroit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/detroit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I played &lt;strong&gt;Detroit: Become Human&lt;/strong&gt; during a quiet period in life, and it left a lasting impression — not because of action or graphics (though both are good), but because of &lt;strong&gt;how it handles storytelling and choice-making&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-just-a-game-but-an-interactive-story&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not Just a Game, But an Interactive Story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, &lt;em&gt;Detroit: Become Human&lt;/em&gt; is about &lt;strong&gt;choices and consequences&lt;/strong&gt;. You play as three different androids — &lt;strong&gt;Connor, Kara, and Markus&lt;/strong&gt; — each with their own storyline that eventually connects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes this game special is &lt;strong&gt;how much control you have over the story&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Almost every decision you make — from small conversations to life-and-death moments — &lt;strong&gt;shapes the outcome&lt;/strong&gt;, sometimes in unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed seeing how &lt;strong&gt;different dialogue options&lt;/strong&gt; could lead to completely different scenes, relationships, and endings. It&amp;rsquo;s like &lt;strong&gt;playing a movie&lt;/strong&gt;, but you’re the director of every scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes-of-humanity-and-morality&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Themes of Humanity and Morality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason I think &lt;em&gt;Detroit&lt;/em&gt; stands out is its &lt;strong&gt;philosophical depth&lt;/strong&gt;. It raises big questions:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zelda and Me</title>
      <link>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/zelda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/zelda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first played &lt;strong&gt;Breath of the Wild&lt;/strong&gt; during the pandemic lockdown.&lt;br&gt;
Classes were online, everything felt repetitive, and most days blurred together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came Hyrule — open, quiet, and far from reality.&lt;br&gt;
I didn’t rush to beat the game. I just walked. Climbed. Cooked food. Waited out the rain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a time when I couldn’t go anywhere, this game gave me somewhere to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em style=&#34;color:green&#34;&gt;Come on, who actually goes to rescue the princess? Hyrule itself is the real paradise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;playing-not-escaping&#34;&gt;Playing, Not Escaping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link doesn’t talk, but he moves forward — and that was enough.&lt;br&gt;
No big speeches, no drama. Just a broken world, and someone doing what they can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some days, it felt like he was the only other person around.&lt;br&gt;
So I kept playing — not to finish, but to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tears-of-the-kingdom-didnt-hit-the-same&#34;&gt;Tears of the Kingdom Didn’t Hit the Same&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;strong&gt;Tears of the Kingdom&lt;/strong&gt; came out, I thought I’d dive back in.&lt;br&gt;
But I didn’t. I played a bit, admired the new mechanics, and put it down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Nightmares — A Dark Fairy Tale You Don’t Forget</title>
      <link>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/littlenightmare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/littlenightmare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;little-nightmares-quiet-horror-that-stays-with-you&#34;&gt;Little Nightmares: Quiet Horror That Stays With You&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played &lt;strong&gt;Little Nightmares&lt;/strong&gt; a while ago, and some of its moments still linger.&lt;br&gt;
It doesn’t explain much — but it doesn’t have to. You just feel it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-game-that-says-nothing-but-means-a-lot&#34;&gt;A Game That Says Nothing, But Means a Lot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s barely any dialogue. You play as &lt;strong&gt;Six&lt;/strong&gt;, a small figure in a yellow raincoat, trying to escape a strange, sinking world called &lt;strong&gt;The Maw&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What got me was the &lt;strong&gt;atmosphere&lt;/strong&gt; — eerie, quiet, and always tense.&lt;br&gt;
You&amp;rsquo;re not fighting back. Just running, hiding, surviving. That sense of helplessness makes everything feel more real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beautiful-in-a-disturbing-way&#34;&gt;Beautiful, in a Disturbing Way&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visually, the game is like a broken fairy tale.&lt;br&gt;
Distorted creatures, oversized rooms, flickering lights — nothing feels quite right, and that’s the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not about jump scares. The fear comes from &lt;strong&gt;being small in a world that doesn’t care&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crusader Kings III: Where History Meets Chaos — A Personal Journey</title>
      <link>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/ck3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/ck3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever dreamed of &lt;strong&gt;being a medieval queen or king&lt;/strong&gt;, plotting the downfall of enemies, surviving political intrigue, or marrying off relatives to secure alliances — &lt;strong&gt;Crusader Kings III (CK3)&lt;/strong&gt; is the ultimate stage to live out those dreams. But for me, CK3 is not just a strategy game. It&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;sandbox for chaos&lt;/strong&gt;, a place where history, power, and human flaws collide in ways no other game can replicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-ck3&#34;&gt;Why CK3?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When life gets overwhelming, some people read books, some people go hiking — I start a dynasty in CK3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what makes CK3 different is that &lt;strong&gt;you never fully &amp;ldquo;control&amp;rdquo; your story&lt;/strong&gt;. You might &lt;strong&gt;start as a powerful queen&lt;/strong&gt;, but within two generations, your dynasty could be split by succession wars, assassinated by angry vassals, or reduced to a minor count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I love that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Life is unpredictable, and so is CK3.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hades — A Roguelike That Feels Personal</title>
      <link>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/hades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruoqi28.github.io/en/en/posts/life/game-log/hades/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I played &lt;strong&gt;Hades&lt;/strong&gt; during my time exploring indie and narrative-driven games, and it quickly became one of my favorites.&lt;br&gt;
Unlike many action games, &lt;strong&gt;Hades combines fast-paced combat with a story that actually matters&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-than-just-a-roguelike&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Than Just a Roguelike&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I was drawn to &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; because of its &lt;strong&gt;smooth action gameplay&lt;/strong&gt; — the combat is fast, responsive, and has a lot of variety depending on the weapon and &amp;ldquo;boons&amp;rdquo; you choose.&lt;br&gt;
But what really surprised me was &lt;strong&gt;how much story and character development there is&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you die (and you die a lot — it’s a roguelike after all), &lt;strong&gt;the story moves forward&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
You get new conversations with characters like &lt;strong&gt;Zagreus, Hades, Nyx, and the Olympian gods&lt;/strong&gt;, and slowly piece together why Zagreus is trying to escape the Underworld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;greek-mythology-but-fresh&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greek Mythology, but Fresh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best parts of &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; is how it brings &lt;strong&gt;Greek mythology&lt;/strong&gt; to life — but in a way that feels modern.&lt;br&gt;
The gods are &lt;strong&gt;funny, flawed, and complicated&lt;/strong&gt;, and your relationships with them evolve as you play.&lt;br&gt;
Unlike some games that just &amp;ldquo;borrow&amp;rdquo; mythology as a setting, &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; really makes you feel like &lt;strong&gt;you are part of that world&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
